<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<imr:Resource xsi:type="nmi:MetrologyInstitute"
              xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
              xmlns:imr="http://schema.bipm.org/xml/imres/1.0wd"
              xmlns:nmi="http://schema.bipm.org/xml/imres/nmi/1.0wd"
              status="active" localid="####">
          
   <resourceType>Organization: Metrology Institute</resourceType>
   <title>US National Institute of Standards and Technology</title>
   <altTitle type="Abbreviation">NIST</altTitle>
   <homeURL>https://www.nist.gov/</homeURL>
   <sponsoringCountry abbrev="USA">United States of America</sponsoringCountry>

   <contact>
     <name>Robert Hanisch</name>
     <emailAddress>robert.hanisch@nist.gov</emailAddress>
   </contact>

   <subject>standards</subject>
   <subject>standard reference data</subject>
   <subject>metrology</subject>
   <subject>materials</subject>
   <subject>physics</subject>
   <subject>computing</subject>
   <subject>cybersecurity</subject>

   <description>
     Founded in 1901, NIST is a non-regulatory federal agency within
     the U.S. Department of Commerce. NIST's mission is to promote
     U.S. innovation and industrial competitiveness by advancing
     measurement science, standards, and technology in ways that
     enhance economic security and improve our quality of life.  NIST
     carries out its mission through the following programs: (1) the
     NIST Laboratories, conducting world-class research, often in
     close collaboration with industry, that advances the nation's
     technology infrastructure and helps U.S. companies continually
     improve products and services; (2) the Hollings Manufacturing
     Extension Partnership, a nationwide network of local centers
     offering technical and business assistance to smaller
     manufacturers to help them create and retain jobs, increase
     profits, and save time and money; and (3) the Baldrige
     Performance Excellence Program, which promotes performance
     excellence among U.S. manufacturers, service companies,
     educational institutions, health care providers, and nonprofit
     organizations; conducts outreach programs; and manages the annual
     Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award which recognizes
     performance excellence and quality achievement.  It also curates and
     publishes a number of standard reference and metrology data
     collections.  
   </description>

   <date type="Created">1901</date>

</imr:Resource>
